Hi, I'm Tim Gipson and I'm going to talk to you about how to measure windows.
Now, window size is based on the finished opening that we have around the windows.
So, in this case these windows have finished drywall and so the width would be from one finished side to the other.
So, to measure that, simply put my tape measure flush to one side and measure over to the other side and I get thirty one inches.
So, just by measuring flush side to flush side I get thirty one inches.
So, my window is thirty one inches high.
Now, the same thing on the height of the window.
Now, the height we can't see because it's up inside this valance, but there will be a top finished surface just like this drywall finish up inside.
So, I can insert my tape measure up to that width and then I what I want to do is I want to measure down to the sill down at the bottom.
In this case I get seventy inches.
So, from the top finished opening of the window to the sill gives me my height of the window.
So, in this case as I've measured I've got a thirty one by seventy inch window.
And how that's useful is draw a rectangle.
Put those dimensions down.
So, now if you're constructing a valance or you're putting curtains up or measuring for curtains, then you have your good measurements for you windows as far as how many panels you'll need or what size you'll need for blinds.
I'm Tim Gipson and that's how to measure a window.